<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../transforms/esr2html.xsl"?>

<ESR xmlns="http://common-criteria.rhcloud.com/ns/esr" name="Transport Layer Security">

	<intro>
		<esrtitle>Essential Security Requirements for Transport Layer Security (TLS)</esrtitle>
		<maintainer>US NIAP and UK CESG</maintainer>
		<identifier>42</identifier>
		<version>1.0</version>
		<status>draft</status>
		<issuedate>31 Aug 2016</issuedate>
		<approver/>
		<supercedes/>
	</intro>

	<section title="Background and Purpose" id="purpose">
		This Essential Security Requirements (ESR) document
    describes a core set of security requirements for implementations of
    Transport Layer Security.  The resulting Extended Package (EP) will
    permit evaluation of such functionality through the Common Criteria paradigm.
    The resulting EP is intended to serve as a consistent "building block" for evaluation of
    TLS functionality in application software, operating systems,
    mobile devices, and other IT products.
	</section>
	<section title="Use Cases" id="usecases">
  Several versions of the TLS protocol
    are in widespread use in applications such as web browsers, email,
    instant messaging, and voice-over-IP (VoIP). Major web sites use TLS to
    protect the communications from their servers. TLS is also commonly used to
    protect communications between hosts and network infrastructure devices
    for administration.
	</section>

	<section title="Resources to be protected" id="resourcesprotected">
    The TLS protocols provide confidentiality and integrity for the data
    transmitted between two communicating endpoints on Internet
    Protocol networks.  This also includes the Datagram TLS protocol (DTLS),
    which is a connectionless version of TLS.
	</section>

	<section title="Attacker access" id="attackeraccess">
	  <p/> The attacker is expected to engage in the following general classes of
      attack against TLS implementations:
	  <ul>
	    <li> Network eavesdropping, in which an attacker may monitor and attempt to
        gain access to data exchanged between the product and other endpoints. </li>
	    <li> Network attack, in which an attacker may initiate malicious communications with the
	    product or alter communications between the product and other endpoints. </li>
	  </ul>
	</section>

	<section title="Essential Security Requirements" id="requirements">
    Functionality-related requirements are:
    <ul>
      <li>
        Confidentiality for transmitted data.
      </li>
      <li>
        Integrity for transmitted data.
      </li>
      <li>
        Identification and authentication of the server-side endpoint,
        and optionally the client-side endpoint.
      </li>
    </ul>
	</section>

	<section title="Assumptions" id="assumptions">
	  The following assumptions are made for the TLS implementation and its operational
	  environment:
    <ul>
			<li>The private key of the TLS server has not been compromised.
      Compromise of this key implies compromise of any data transmitted
      over the TLS connection, as well as an inability to identify and
      authenticate the server.  Similarly, any compromise of a client private
      key implies an inability to identify and authenticate that client.
      </li>
			<li>System administrators and users are not malicious in nature,
        and do not inadvertently or intentionally misconfigure the TLS
        software (e.g. null cipher).
      </li>
		</ul>
	</section>


</ESR>
