<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../transforms/pp2html.xsl"?>

<PP xmlns="http://common-criteria.rhcloud.com/ns/cc" name="TLS"
    xmlns:h="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <!-- <inline-comment color='green'> Hello World TLS </inline-comment> -->
  <!-- <inline-comment color='blue' linebreak='yes'> Hello World TLS </inline-comment> -->
  <PPReference title="PP Reference">
    <ReferenceTable>
      <PPTitle>Extended Package for TLS</PPTitle>
      <PPVersion>4.0</PPVersion>
      <PPAuthor>National Information Assurance Partnership</PPAuthor>
      <PPPubDate>2015-08-14</PPPubDate>
      <PPCertificationID>unassigned</PPCertificationID>
      <CCVersion>3.1R4</CCVersion>
      <Keywords>TLS</Keywords>
      <entry>
        <name>Registration</name>
        <description>National Information Assurance Partnership</description>
      </entry>
    </ReferenceTable>
  </PPReference>

  <RevisionHistory role="draft">
    <entry>
      <version>Round 1</version>
      <date>2015-04-23</date>
      <subject>First draft of version 4.0 for comment</subject>
    </entry>
  </RevisionHistory>

  <RevisionHistory role="final">
    <entry>
      <version>4.0</version>
      <date>2015-08-14</date>
      <subject>Release - significant revision</subject>
    </entry>
  </RevisionHistory>

  <chapter title="Introduction" id="int">
    <section title="Overview" id="ppoverview"> 
      Transport Layer Security (TLS) is a cryptographic protocola designed to provide communications security over a computer network. Several versions of the protocol are in widespread use in applications such as web browsers, email, Internet faxing, instant messaging, and voice-over-IP (VoIP). Major web sites use TLS to secure all communications between their servers and web browsers. Major Operating Systems and hardware vendors also make use of TLS to provide secure communications between hosts and devices.

      The primary goal of the TLS protocol is to provide privacy and data integrity between two communicating products. 

      TLS supports many different methods for exchanging keys, encrypting data, and authenticating message integrity (see <component-refer ref="fcs_tls_ext.1.1"/>). As a result, secure configuration of TLS involves many configurable parameters, and not all choices provide all of the privacy-related properties described in the list above.

      This Extended Package (EP) provides a baseline set of Securtiy Fuctional Requirments (SFRs) for products that implement TLS, regardless of the composition of the underlying platform. The requirments are intended to improve the secuirty of products by encoruaging the use of correctly configured TLS parameters. 

      To a product to claim conformence against the following PPs and cPPs it must also be conforment against this EP:
      <<LIST OF PP/CPP that must be conforment>>

    </section>
    <section title="Terms" id="glossary"> The following sections provide both Common Criteria and
      technology terms used in this Protection Profile. <subsection title="Common Criteria Terms"
        id="ccterms">
        <glossary>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Common Criteria">CC</abbr></term>
            <description>Common Criteria for Information Technology Security
              Evaluation.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Common Evaluation Methodology">CEM</abbr></term>
            <description>Common Evaluation Methodology for Information Technology Security
              Evaluation.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Protection Profile">PP</abbr></term>
            <description>An implementation-independent set of security requirements for a category
              of products.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Security Target">ST</abbr></term>
            <description>A set of implementation-dependent security requirements for a specific
              product.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</abbr></term>
            <description>
	      The product under evaluation. In this case, the Operating System as described in section 
	      <xref linkend="TOEboundary"/> and its
              supporting documentation.
	    </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="TOE Security Functionality">TSF</abbr></term>
            <description>The security functionality of the product under evaluation.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="TOE Summary Specification">TSS</abbr></term>
            <description>A description of how a <abbr linkend="TOE"/> satisfies the SFRs in a <abbr
                linkend="ST"/>. </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Security Functional Requirement">SFR</abbr></term>
            <description>A requirement for security enforcement by the <abbr linkend="TOE"/>.
            </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Security Assurance Requirement">SAR</abbr></term>
            <description>A requirement to assure the security of the <abbr linkend="TOE"/>.
            </description>
          </entry>
        </glossary>
      </subsection>
      <subsection title="Technology Terms" id="techterms">
        <glossary>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="TLS"></abbr></term>
            <description>
              Transport Layer Security
	          </description>
          </entry>
        </glossary>
      </subsection>
	  </section>
    <section title="Compliant Targets of Evaluation" id="TOEdescription">
      <subsection title="TOE Boundary" id="TOEboundary">
        <figure entity="images/Toe.png" title="Figure 1: General TOE " id="toe"/>
      </subsection>
      <subsection title="TOE Platform" id="TOEplatform">
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section title="Use Cases" id="usecases">
      Requirements in this extended package are designed to address the security problems in the use cases below. These use cases are intentionally very broad, as TLS can be used to perform many tasks.  
      <usecases>
                <usecase title="Client-Server secure communciation">
                    <description> 
                        TLS enables client-server products to communicate across a network in a way designed to prevent eavesdropping and tampering by providing an encrypted commincations channel that provides guranteed data integrity and privicy between the hosts.
                      </description>
                </usecase>
      </usecases>
    </section>
  </chapter>
  <chapter title="Conformance Claims" id="ccl">
    <cclaims>
      <cclaim id="Conformance Statement">
        <description> To be conformant to this PP, a <abbr linkend="ST"/> must demonstrate Exact
          Conformance, a subset of Strict Conformance as defined in <cite linkend="bibCC"/> Part 1
          (ASE_CCL). The <abbr linkend="ST"/> must include all components in this PP that are: <h:ul>
            <h:li>unconditional (which are always required)</h:li>
            <h:li>selection-based (which are required when certain <h:i>selections</h:i> are chosen in the
              unconditional requirements)</h:li>
          </h:ul>and may include components that are <h:ul>
            <h:li>optional or</h:li>
            <h:li>objective.</h:li>
          </h:ul>
          <InsertAppendixExplainer/> The <abbr linkend="ST"/> may iterate any of these components,
          but it must not include any additional component (e.g. from CC Part 2 or 3 or a PP not
          conformant with this one, or extended by the <abbr linkend="ST"/>) not defined in this PP
          or a PP conformant to this one. 
          <h:br/>
		  Some components in this Protection Profile have a dependency on
		  other components.  In accordance with <cite linkend="bibCC"/> Part 1, <appref linkend="satisfiedreqs"/> 
          includes justifications for those cases where the PP does not explicitly contain the component
		  upon which there is a dependency.
        </description>
      </cclaim>
      <cclaim id="CC Conformance Claims">
        <description>This PP is conformant to Parts 2 (extended) and 3 (extended) of Common Criteria
          Version 3.1, Revision 4.<cite linkend="bibCC"/>.</description>
      </cclaim>
      <cclaim id="PP Claim">
        <description>This PP does not claim conformance to any other Protection
          Profile.</description>
      </cclaim>
      <cclaim id="Package Claim">
        <description>This PP does not claim conformance to any packages.</description>
      </cclaim>
    </cclaims>
  </chapter>
  <chapter title="Security Problem Definition" id="spd">The security problem is described in terms
    of the threats that the product is expected to address, assumptions about the
    operational environment, and any organizational security policies that the product
    is expected to enforce. <section title="Threats" id="threats">
      <threats>
        <threat id="T.TLS">
          <description> </description>
          <objective-refer ref="O.TLS">
            <rationale>The threat T.TLS is countered by O.TLS as this
              provides for .</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </threat>
      </threats>
    </section>
    <section title="Assumptions" id="assumptions">
      <assumptions>
        <assumption id="A.TLS">
          <description> The product relies on TLS and its execution. This underlying platform is out of scope of this PP. </description>
          <objective-refer ref="OE.PLATFORM">
            <rationale> The operational environment objective OE.PLATFORM is realized through
              A.PLATFORM. </rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </assumption>
      </assumptions>
    </section>
<!--    <section title="Organizational Security Policies" id="OSPs">
      <OSPs>
        <OSP id="P.ENTERPRISE">
          <description>If the OS is bound to a directory or management server, the configuration of
            the OS software must be capable of adhering to the enterprise security policies
            distributed by them.</description>
          <objective-refer ref="O.MANAGEMENT">
            <rationale>The organizational security policy P.ENTERPRISE is enforced through the
              objective O.MANAGEMENT as this objective represents how the enterprise and user assert
              management over the <abbr linkend="OS"/>.</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </OSP>
      </OSPs>
    </section> -->
  </chapter>
  <chapter title="Security Objectives for the product" id="obj">
    <section title="Security Objectives for the TOE" id="SecurityObjectivesTOE">
      <SOs>
        <SO id="O.PROTECTED_COMMS">
          <description>
            To address both passive (eavesdropping) and active (packet modification) network attack threats, conformant products provide mechanisms to create trusted channels for CSP and sensitive data. Both CSP and sensitive data should not be exposed outside of the product. 
          </description>
          <!-- CHECK TO MAKE SURE THESE ARE ALL IN THE DOCUMET -->
          <component-refer ref="fcs_tlsc_ext.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="fcs_tlsc_ext.2"/>
          <component-refer ref="fcs_tlsc_ext.3"/>
          <component-refer ref="fcs_tlsc_ext.4"/>
          <component-refer ref="fcs_dtls_ext.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="fcs_rbg_ext.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="fcs_ckm.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="fcs_ckm.2"/>
          <component-refer ref="fcs_cop.1.1(1)"/>
          <component-refer ref="fdp_ifc_ext.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="fia_x509_ext.1"/>
          <component-refer ref="fia_x509_ext.2"/>
        <component-refer ref="ftp_itc_ext.1"/>
        <!-- CHECK TO MAKE SURE THESE ARE ALL IN THE DOCUMET -->
        </SO>
      </SOs>
    </section>

  </chapter>
  <chapter title="Security Requirements" id="req">This chapter describes the security requirements
    which have to be fulfilled by the product. Those requirements comprise functional
    components from Part 2 and assurance components from Part 3 of <cite linkend="bibCC"/>. The
    following notations are used: <h:ul>
      <h:li>
        <h:b>Refinement</h:b> operation (denoted by <h:b>bold text</h:b>): is used to add details to a
        requirement, and thus further restricts a requirement.</h:li>
      <h:li>
        <h:b>Selection</h:b> (denoted by <h:i>italicized text</h:i>): is used to select one or more options
        provided by the [CC] in stating a requirement.</h:li>
      <h:li>
        <h:b>Assignment</h:b> operation (denoted by <h:span class="assignable-content">italicized text</h:span>): is used to assign a
        specific value to an unspecified parameter, such as the length of a password. Showing the
        value in square brackets indicates assignment.</h:li>
      <h:li>
        <h:b>Iteration</h:b> operation: are identified with a number inside parentheses (e.g.
        "(1)")</h:li>
    </h:ul>
    <section title="Security Functional Requirements" id="SFRs">The Security Functional Requirements
      included in this section are derived from Part 2 of the Common Criteria for Information
      Technology Security Evaluation, Version 3.1, Revision 4, with additional extended functional
      components.
      <subsection title="TLS" id="TLS">
        <f-component id="TLS_TLS.1" name="TLS" status="threshold">
          <f-element id="TLS_TLS.1.1">
            <title> 
            </title>
            <note role="application"></note>
            <aactivity>
	    </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </chapter>

  <appendix title="Optional Requirements" id="optional"> As indicated in <secref linkend="ccl"/>,
    the baseline requirements (those that must be performed by the <abbr linkend="OS"/>) are
    contained in the body of this PP. Additionally, there are three other types of requirements
    specified in <appref linkend="optional"/>, <appref linkend="sel-based"/>, and <appref
      linkend="objective"/>. The first type (in this Appendix) are requirements that can be included
    in the <abbr linkend="ST"/>, but are not required in order for a OS to claim conformance to
    this PP. The second type (in <appref linkend="sel-based"/>) are requirements based on selections
    in the body of the PP: if certain selections are made, then additional requirements in that
    appendix must be included. The third type (in <appref linkend="objective"/> are components that
    are not required in order to conform to this PP, but will be included in the baseline
    requirements in future versions of this PP, so adoption by vendors is encouraged. Note that the
    ST author is responsible for ensuring that requirements that may be associated with those in
      <appref linkend="optional"/>, <appref linkend="sel-based"/>, and <appref linkend="objective"/>
    but are not listed (e.g., FMT-type requirements) are also included in the ST. </appendix>

  <appendix title="Selection-Based Requirements" id="sel-based"> As indicated in the introduction to
    this PP, the baseline requirements (those that must be performed by the OS or its underlying
    platform) are contained in the body of this PP. There are additional requirements based on
    selections in the body of the PP: if certain selections are made, then additional requirements
    below will need to be included. </appendix>

  <appendix title="Objective Requirements" id="objective"> This appendix includes requirements that
    specify security functionality which also addresses threats. The requirements are not currently
    mandated in the body of this PP as they describe security functionality not yet widely-available
    in commercial technology. However, these requirements may be included in the ST such that the
    OS is still conformant to this PP, and it is expected that they be included as soon as
    possible. </appendix>

  

  <appendix title="Entropy Documentation and Assessment" id="entropyappendix"> This appendix
    describes the required supplementary information for the entropy source used by the OS. <h:br/>
    The documentation of the entropy source should be detailed enough that, after reading, the
    evaluator will thoroughly understand the entropy source and why it can be relied upon to provide
    sufficient entropy. This documentation should include multiple detailed sections: design
    description, entropy justification, operating conditions, and health testing. This documentation
    is not required to be part of the TSS. <section id="entropydesign" title="Design Description">
      Documentation shall include the design of the entropy source as a whole, including the
      interaction of all entropy source components. Any information that can be shared regarding the
      design should also be included for any third-party entropy sources that are included in the
      product. <h:br/> The documentation will describe the operation of the entropy source to include,
      how entropy is produced, and how unprocessed (raw) data can be obtained from within the
      entropy source for testing purposes. The documentation should walk through the entropy source
      design indicating where the entropy comes from, where the entropy output is passed next, any
      post-processing of the raw outputs (hash, XOR, etc.), if/where it is stored, and finally, how
      it is output from the entropy source. Any conditions placed on the process (e.g., blocking)
      should also be described in the entropy source design. Diagrams and examples are encouraged.
      <h:br/> This design must also include a description of the content of the security boundary of
      the entropy source and a description of how the security boundary ensures that an adversary
      outside the boundary cannot affect the entropy rate. <h:br/> If implemented, the design
      description shall include a description of how third-party applications can add entropy to the
      RBG. A description of any RBG state saving between power-off and power-on shall be included. </section>
    <section id="entropyjustification" title="Entropy Justification"> There should be a technical
      argument for where the unpredictability in the source comes from and why there is confidence
      in the entropy source delivering sufficient entropy for the uses made of the RBG output (by
      this particular OS). This argument will include a description of the expected min-entropy
      rate (i.e. the minimum entropy (in bits) per bit or byte of source data) and explain that
      sufficient entropy is going into the OS randomizer seeding process. This discussion will be
      part of a justification for why the entropy source can be relied upon to produce bits with
      entropy. <h:br/> The amount of information necessary to justify the expected min-entropy rate
      depends on the type of entropy source included in the product. <h:br/> For developer provided
      entropy sources, in order to justify the min-entropy rate, it is expected that a large number
      of raw source bits will be collected, statistical tests will be performed, and the min-entropy
      rate determined from the statistical tests. While no particular statistical tests are required
      at this time, it is expected that some testing is necessary in order to determine the amount
      of min-entropy in each output. <h:br/> For third-party provided entropy sources, in which the
      OS vendor has limited access to the design and raw entropy data of the source, the
      documentation will indicate an estimate of the amount of min-entropy obtained from this
      third-party source. It is acceptable for the vendor to “assume” an amount of min-entropy,
      however, this assumption must be clearly stated in the documentation provided. In particular,
      the min-entropy estimate must be specified and the assumption included in the ST. <h:br/>
      Regardless of type of entropy source, the justification will also include how the DRBG is
      initialized with the entropy stated in the ST, for example by verifying that the min-entropy
      rate is multiplied by the amount of source data used to seed the DRBG or that the rate of
      entropy expected based on the amount of source data is explicitly stated and compared to the
      statistical rate. If the amount of source data used to seed the DRBG is not clear or the
      calculated rate is not explicitly related to the seed, the documentation will not be
      considered complete. <h:br/> The entropy justification shall not include any data added from any
      third-party application or from any state saving between restarts. </section>
    <section id="entropyoperatingconditions" title="Operating Conditions"> The entropy rate may be
      affected by conditions outside the control of the entropy source itself. For example, voltage,
      frequency, temperature, and elapsed time after power-on are just a few of the factors that may
      affect the operation of the entropy source. As such, documentation will also include the range
      of operating conditions under which the entropy source is expected to generate random data. It
      will clearly describe the measures that have been taken in the system design to ensure the
      entropy source continues to operate under those conditions. Similarly, documentation shall
      describe the conditions under which the entropy source is known to malfunction or become
      inconsistent. Methods used to detect failure or degradation of the source shall be included. </section>
    <section id="entropyhealthtesting" title="Health Testing"> More specifically, all entropy source
      health tests and their rationale will be documented. This includes a description of the health
      tests, the rate and conditions under which each health test is performed (e.g., at start,
      continuously, or on-demand), the expected results for each health test, and rationale
      indicating why each test is believed to be appropriate for detecting one or more failures in
      the entropy source. </section>
  </appendix>

  <appendix title="References" id="biblio">
    <bibliography>
      <entry id="bibCC">
        <tag>CC</tag>
        <description>Common Criteria for Information Technology Security Evaluation - <h:ul>
            <h:li><h:a href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CCPART1V3.1R4.pdf">Part
                1: Introduction and General Model</h:a>, CCMB-2012-09-001, Version 3.1 Revision 4,
              September 2012.</h:li>
            <h:li><h:a href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CCPART2V3.1R4.pdf">Part
                2: Security Functional Components</h:a>, CCMB-2012-09-002, Version 3.1 Revision 4,
              September 2012.</h:li>
            <h:li><h:a href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CCPART3V3.1R4.pdf">Part
                3: Security Assurance Components</h:a>, CCMB-2012-09-003, Version 3.1 Revision 4,
              September 2012.</h:li>
          </h:ul></description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="bibCEM">
        <tag>CEM</tag>
        <description>
          <h:a href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CEMV3.1R4.pdf">Common
            Evaluation Methodology for Information Technology Security - Evaluation Methodology</h:a>,
          CCMB-2012-09-004, Version 3.1, Revision 4, September 2012. </description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="bibCESG">
        <tag>CESG</tag>
        <description>CESG - <h:a
            href="https://www.gov.uk/government/collections/end-user-devices-security-guidance"> End
            User Devices Security and Configuration Guidance</h:a></description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="bibCSA">
        <tag>CSA</tag>
        <description>
          <h:a href="http://csrc.nist.gov/groups/SMA/ispab/documents/csa_87.txt">Computer Security Act
            of 1987</h:a>, H.R. 145, June 11, 1987. </description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="bibOMB">
        <tag>OMB</tag>
        <description>
          <h:a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/sites/default/files/omb/memoranda/fy2006/m06-19.pdf"
            >Reporting Incidents Involving Personally Identifiable Information and Incorporating the
            Cost for Security in Agency Information Technology Investments</h:a>, OMB M-06-19, July
          12, 2006. </description>
      </entry>
    </bibliography>
  </appendix>

  <appendix title="Acronyms" id="acronyms">
    <acronyms>
      <entry>
        <term>AES</term>
        <description>Advanced Encryption Standard</description>
      </entry>
  </appendix>
</PP>
